javascript a high level single threaded garbage collected interpreted or just in
javascript是一种基于原型的高级单线程
time compiled prototype-based multi-paradigm dynamic language with a
垃圾回收解释和即时编译的具有非阻塞循环事件
non-blocking event loop made famous for building websites it was created in 1995
的多范式动态语言，因构建网站而闻名
in just one week by brendan ike with the goal of adding an easy to learn
它是由Brendan Eich 1995年在短短一周内于创建的，
scripting language to the netscape browser it was originally named Mocha
其目的是在网景浏览器中添加了一种易于学习的脚本语言
but the genius marketing people of the time wanted it to sound like that sexy
它最初被命名为Mocha，但当时的天才营销人员希望它听起来像一种性感的新java语言
new java language today it's a fully featured language that continues to
在今天它是一种功能齐全的语言
evolve through the ECMAScript standard it's most well known for building
它通过ECMAScript标准继续发展
front-end web applications because it's the only language other than web
因为它是除Web程序集之外唯一支持浏览器原生的语言
assembly that is natively supported in browsers however anything that can be
但是任何可以用javascript构建的东西都将用javascript构建
built with javascript will be built with javascript like server-side applications
例如带有 node.js 的服务器端应用程序和
with node.js mobile applications with react native or ionic and desktop apps
带有React 的移动应用程序
with electron it's an interpreted scripting language but tools like the v8
以及带electron桌面应用程序，它是一种解释性脚本语言，
engine and chromium use a just-in-time compiler to convert it to machine code
v8引擎和 chromium 等工具使用即时编译器在运行时将其转换为机器代码
at runtime it's also excellent at handling i o intensive jobs despite the
它在处理IO密集型作业方面也非常出色，
fact that it's a single threaded language made possible by a non-blocking
尽管它是通过非阻塞事件循环实现的单线程语言
event loop that can queue up work in the background without blocking the main
在后台排队工作而不阻塞主线程
thread to get started create a file ending in.js your code will start
开始创建一个以.js结尾的文件,您的代码将从全局上下文
executing from the global context use the console to log a value with the
开始执行使用控制台和用内置调试器记录一个值
built-in debugger now think about where you want to run this file is it a
现在想想你想在哪里运行这个文件,是前端浏览器
front-end browser or a back-end node.js server in the browser you can reference
还是浏览器中的后端node.js服务器
it with a script tag then the browser will execute it when you open that html
您可以使用脚本标签引用它，然后使用浏览器在网站上
file on a website javascript is often used to grab an element from the dom
打开该 html 文件执行,javascript通常从 Dom 文档中抓取一个元素
document query selector will grab the first button then we can assign it to a
查询选择器会抓取一个按钮，然后我们可以
variable with either var let or const var is the og way to do it but is
使用 var let 或const将其分配给一个变量,但通常避免使用 let
typically avoided let is for variables that can be reassigned while const is
用于重新分配的变量，而 const 无法重新分配新的变量
for variables that cannot be reassigned now to make the button interactive we
现在要使按钮具有交互性，我们可以通过为 onClick
can add an event listener to it by defining a function for the on click
事件定义一个函数来为其添加一个事件侦听器
event we can use the function keyword here or the more concise arrow syntax
我们可以使用 function 关键字或更简洁的箭头函数
now the event loop will execute this function whenever a new click occurs
现在只要发生新的点击，事件就会循环执行这个函数，
functions are first class objects to support functional programming patterns
函数是支持函数式编程模式的第一类对象
but javascript also supports classes and inheritance for object oriented patterns
但 Javascript 也支持面向对象模式的类和继承，
even though it's single threaded it can do work asynchronously with the promise
即使它是单线程的，它也可以使用 Promise api 异步工作，
api which also supports the async await syntax js code can also run on the
它也支持 async await 语法,node js可以让
server thanks to the nodejs runtime instead of buttons on a web page it
js代码在服务器上运行而不仅仅是网页上的按钮
interacts with things like the file system api execute your code on the
它与文件系统api之类的东西交互，通过拉起终端
server by pulling up the terminal and entering the node command this has been
在服务器上输入节点命令来执行你的代码
javascript in 100 seconds hit the like button and subscribe if you want to see
这是Javascript100秒简介
will see you in the next one
谢谢，下次见